Caleb Rowlands

RowlandsC14@cardiff.ac.uk • +447803295194

Profile

Computing graduate with an understanding of development technologies and computer science principles. Experience using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Python, Flask and well-versed in Agile methodologies. Recently completed a MSc dissertation project utilising the MERN stack and Google Maps API. Committed to apply and develop my existing skills, whilst adapting to new programming languages and technologies in an entry-level developer/engineer role. Over 4 years of professional experience in ground engineering, specialising in the delivery of large-scale infrastructure projects across the UK. This background has equipped me with exceptional communication, professionalism, and quality assurance skills, which I am keen to transfer to a new industry.

Education

Cardiff University / Prifysgol Caerdydd • Cardiff • UK MSc Computing – TBC (77% after taught element)

2022 - 2023

Technologies covered: HTML, CSS, JS, Python, SQL, Java, Flask, Tkinter, VSCode, Git, Openshift

University of Plymouth • Plymouth • UK
BSc Geology – 1st Class
2014 – 2017

Work experience

Structural Soils • Bristol • United Kingdom Ground Investigation Reporting Engineer

04/2019 - 09/2022

- Conducted thorough quality reviews, interpretation, and preparation of data in various required formats for project clients
- Presented data and findings in a professional manner to project clients
- Collaborated effectively with project reporting and project management teams to address client data queries and promptly respond to comments on technical reports
- Demonstrated exceptional document control skills as the primary controller for two major contracts, South Portal and Euston Station Supplementary GI
- Assumed responsibility for project data management, specifically for groundwater monitoring across entire contracts

 Demonstrated strong problem-solving abilities by assessing and resolving client data queries

Structural Soils • Bristol • United Kingdom

Data Processor

11/2017 - 04/2019

- Conducted thorough QA checks on driller's logs and electronically collected exploratory hole records to ensure accuracy, consistency, and compliance with project requirements.
- Demonstrated exceptional communication skills by liaising with senior engineers and clients, ensuring effective collaboration and meeting daily deadlines.
- Updated project sales monitor and exploratory hole register, maintaining accurate and up-to-date records.
- Efficiently sent field data to clients and senior engineers on site, ensuring timely delivery and accessibility of information.
- Transcribed logging performed on paper by engineers on site into the project database, ensuring precision and completeness of records.
- Conducted additional thorough checks and issued accurate records, contributing to the overall success and efficiency of the project.

Instituto Volcanológico de Canarias (INVOLCAN) - Gran Canaria Geochemistry Intern

09/2017 - 10/2017

- Collaborated on scientific research project in geothermal exploration, focusing on soil degassing surveys
- Collected and analysed soil gas samples using chemical and isotopic analysis techniques

Languages

Awards		
Welsh	Fluent	
English	Fluent	

Palaeontological Association Prize for Best Performance in Palaeontology

2015

Publications

Soil gas He and H2 for surface geothermal exploration in Gran Canaria, Canary Islands • Geophysical Research Abstracts, EGU General Assembly 2018

https://meetingorganizer.copernicus.org/EGU2018/EGU2018-10366-2.pdf